URVI PRAJAPATI

UI/UX Designer

+1(647) 818-7633 | prajapatiurvi977@gmail.com | Toronto-ON, M6M 1S4

<u>LinkedIn</u> Portfolio

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced UI/UX Designer with prior experience in UI development. Expert in creating user-centered digital experiences that combine aesthetics and utility. Driven by empathy and data insights, I work to improve user journeys. My thorough understanding of human behaviour ensures that designs resonate deeply, boosting the overall user experience.

UX/UI PROJECTS

Tim Hortons | UX/UI Designer

- Conducted user research, including interviews and surveys, to discover pain spots and preferences. Created a mobile app prototype that fulfills 95% of user needs.
- Used agile design to create visually engaging interfaces, increasing user engagement by 40% and streamlining restaurant exploration.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to obtain feedback on UX/UI designs, resulting in iterative improvements and exceeding stakeholder expectations.

Toronto Zoo | UX/UI Designer / Researcher

- Developed a complete user research plan and conducted usability testing on the navigation and Hi-fi prototype, resulting in a 20% increase in user satisfaction.
- Implemented design enhancements based on user feedback, resulting in a 15% decrease in user errors during the purchasing membership process.
- Collaborated with technical experts to create responsive designs for mobile and websites, resulting in a 30% increase in conversion rates.

Humber Current | UX/UI Designer/ Researcher/ Team Lead

- Redesigned Humber Current's portfolio portal with a user-centered approach and Agile methodology, leading to a 30% increase in student-graduate relationships and a lively online community for collaboration and accessing opportunities.
- Successfully implemented the revised portal through seamless collaboration with software development and content strategy teams, ensuring timely project delivery.
- Improved portfolio site user experience by 40%, increasing student and alumni engagement and usage.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Design Intern | Transformers Academy, Toronto, Canada

Sep 2023 - Nov 2023

- Championed the integration of trauma-informed principles into curriculum design, leading to the creation of a resource guide that has been utilized by 8 educational institutions, enhancing support for diverse learning needs.
- Conducted user research and analyzed to develop data-driven UI guidelines for the company's website, resulting in a 20% increase in user satisfaction and improved key usability metrics by 15%.
- Implemented a design system that integrated accessibility standards, ensuring all web components met WCAG compliance; this initiative expanded the website's reach to 15% more users with disabilities.

UX DESIGNER | Accenture, India

Aug 2021 - Nov 2022

- Produced pixel-perfect, responsive UI implementations from design mockups, integrating them seamlessly with backend services using HTML5, SCSS, and Angular for cross-browser compatibility.
- Played a pivotal role in the design and implementation of user interfaces for insurance web applications using Angular and React resulted in 75% user engagement.
- Conducted usability testing, refined user interfaces, and collaborated with back-end teams to integrate front-end components with server-side logic.
- Contributed to a project that improved user conversion rates by 20% through optimized front-end features.

UI/UX Designer & Developer | Netlink Software, India

Jan 2021 – Aug 2021

- Led the redesign of a key product feature that resulted in a 30% improvement in user interaction and satisfaction.
- Enhanced user experience by designing intuitive interfaces and conducting rigorous user testing to gather actionable feedback for iterations.
- Conducted User Interviews, Usability test, market research for the product improvement.
- Built and deployed 30+ reusable UI components, reducing development time for future projects by 30%.
- Improved product's accessibility scores by 50% by implementing WCAG 2.0 standards across all projects.

UI Developer | Zeus Learning PVT. LTD., India

Sep 2017 – Jan 2021

- Developed over 50 interactive simulation screens, enhancing learning experiences for over 10,000 users.
- Developed user-centric e-learning platforms using Angular and SCSS, focusing on responsive design and mobile-first principles.
- Developed e-learning modules that reduced learning time by 25% while improving user comprehension.
- Created comprehensive teaching and learning modules, materials, and resources, ensuring they are adaptable for inperson, blended, and online delivery methods.

EDUCATION

Humber College

Post Graduate Certificate in UX Design

Dec 2023

University of Mumbai

Bachelor's of Engineering in Information Technology

Mumbai, India May 2017

CERTIFICATION

REB Certification | TCPS 2: CORE 2022 | Canada 01/2023

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Design: Wireframes, Visual Design, Storyboards, Mood boards Brainstorming, Typography, Graphic Design, Motion Design, Accessibility, Digital Prototyping, Web/App Design, User Experience (UX) Design for iOS/ android, User Interface (UI) Design, Information Architecture, User flow, flows, Card sorting, Design thinking process, User interview, Journey mapping, Project Management, Interaction Design, Usability Testing, User Research, Data Visualization, Data analytics, Colour theory, Design Principles, Product design, Web Accessibility WCAG

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, Azure

Tools: Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, Miro, InVision, Framer, Webflow, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects), Canva, Jira, Microsoft Office, FigJam, Squarespace

Additional Skills: SEO Principles, Cross-Browser Compatibility, REST API Integration, Agile/SCRUM, Performance Optimization, problem-solving, analytical skills, communication skills, collaborative mindset